Preliminary Guide to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College Office of Development records, 1953-2005 MVC0028.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mount Vernon Seminary and College Office of Development records
1953-2005
1997-2001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mount Vernon College
Mount Vernon Seminary
MVC0028.RG
9 Linear Feet 6 record cartons
Mount Vernon Seminary and College was an all-women's high school and junior college founded in 1875 by Elizabeth J. Somers. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999. This collection contains the records of the Mount Vernon College Office of Development. Records date from 1953 to 2005, with the bulk of the material dating between 1997 and 2001.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the records of the Mount Vernon College Office of Development. Records date from 1953 to 2005, with the bulk of the material dating between 1997 and 2001 during which Mount Vernon College transitioned from an independent educational institution to a satellite campus of the George Washington University. Subjects include Mount Vernon Today newsletter, budgets and operating plans, campaign planning and capital projects, prospective donors and alumnae, Women in Politics and Journalism Residential Program, endowment funds and foundations, Dear Daughters, Mount Vernon Council, honorary degree recipients, building dedications, and special events. This collection is minimally processed and may contain restricted material that is not currently available for research. Please contact Special Collections for more information.
Conditions Governing Access
This entire collection is closed for 30 years from date of record creation. All inquries need to go to the University Archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by GW Division of Development and Alumni Relations, 10/14/2009 (2009.063)
Biographical / Historical
Mount Vernon Seminary and College was an all-women's high school and junior college founded in 1875 by Elizabeth J. Somers. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999. The Office of Development at Mount Vernon College was originally named the Office of Advancement. Development activities for the George Washington University's Mount Vernon Campus currently fall under the GW Division of Development and Alumni Relations under the Vice President for Advancement.
Arrangement
This collection is unprocessed and files are in the order as received.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is unprocessed and contains confidential material relating to prospective donors to Mount Vernon College. Files containing potentially confidential material have been stamped "Restricted" and are marked "Restricted" at the file level. Before formal processing can occur, staff should screen material before serving in the reading room and remove any files deemed potentially confidential.
Bib#
7779607
George Washington University
- MVC Today Winter, 2002-2003 (Box UP0001, Folder 1)
- Mount Vernon Today Spring 2003 (Box UP0001, Folder 2)
- Mount Vernon Today Fall 2002 (Box UP0001, Folder 3)
- Mount Vernon Today Fall 2001 Expenses (Box UP0001, Folder 4)
- History Book [Dear Daughters], 08/2001-10/2001 (Box UP0001, Folder 5)
- Mount Vernon Today Printed Issues, 2000-2001 (Box UP0001, Folder 6)
- Mount Vernon Today Summer 2003 (Box UP0001, Folder 7)
- SARC Community Service, 04/28/2003-05/02/2003 (Box UP0001, Folder 8)
- June 19 Frawley Trip, 05/21/2003-06/17/2003 (Box UP0001, Folder 9)
- MV Suspects, 1996-2002 (Box UP0001, Folder 10)
  Conditions Governing Access
  This folder contains potentially confidential information about prospective donors to Mount Vernon College. Staff should review folder contents prior to serving in reading room.
  This folder may contain restricted information. Please see Special Collections staff for assistance.
- MVC Major Gift Prospects, 1995-1998 (Box UP0001, Folder 11)
- Major Prospects, 1991-1998 (Box UP0001, Folder 12)
- Women in Politics 09/03/1997 (Box UP0001, Folder 13)
- Women in Politics and Journalism, 09/03/1997 (Box UP0001, Folder 14)
- Women in Politics and Journalism 1999, 10/07/1999 (Box UP0001, Folder 15)
- Women in Politics and Journalism 1998, 09/29/1998 (Box UP0001, Folder 16)
- Women in Politics and Journalism 2000, 10/10/2000 (Box UP0001, Folder 17)
- Budget 1998-1999 (Box UP0001, Folder 18)
- FY 01-02 Budget, 2001-2002 (Box UP0001, Folder 19)
- School of Business and Public Management's Women's Entrepreneurial Leadership Program 2002 (Box UP0001, Folder 20)
- Capital Projects, 2000-2001 (Box UP0001, Folder 21)
- Prospects, 1991 (Box UP0001, Folder 22)
- Campaign Planning, 1999-2001 (Box UP0001, Folder 23)
- Case Information, 1991-1997 (Box UP0001, Folder 24)
- Mount Vernon and GW brochures and bulletins (loose), 1988-1997 (Box UP0001, Folder 25)
- Photography, 1998-2001 (Box UP0002, Folder 1)
- MVC Merchandise, 1998-2000 (Box UP0002, Folder 2)
- Centuries Campaign, 1999-2000 (Box UP0002, Folder 3)
- Case for Support, 1999-2000 (Box UP0002, Folder 4)
- Stewardship, 2003 (Box UP0002, Folder 5)
- History Project [Dear Daughters], 2001 (Box UP0002, Folder 6)
- Oral History Project, undated (Box UP0002, Folder 7)
- Council Meeting, Nov. 2, 2001, 11/02/2001 (Box UP0002, Folder 8)
- Alumnae Association, 2001 (Box UP0002, Folder 9)
- Council for MVC, 2001-2002 (Box UP0002, Folder 10)
- Council for MV, June 8 Meeting, 06/08/2001 (Box UP0002, Folder 11)
- Daunton Transfer FY '02, 2002 (Box UP0002, Folder 12)
- Clock Tower Dedication Expenses, 2002 (Box UP0002, Folder 13)
- Somers Center R-Fund FY '03 Audit, 02/2003-04/2003 (Box UP0002, Folder 14)
- Barbara Ingalls Shook Foundation, 1972-2004 (Box UP0002, Folder 22)
- Board Member List, 1953-1991 (Box UP0002, Folder 29)
  This folder contains potentially confidential information. Staff should review folder contents prior to serving in reading room.
- MVC Trustees, 06/11/1990 (Box UP0002, Folder 30)
- Elizabeth J. Somers, Founder and Headmistress, undated (Box UP0002, Folder 31)
- Mount Vernon Today [loose], 2000-2004 (Box UP0002, Folder 32)
- Sunshine Lady Foundation, 11/14/2001 (Box UP0003, Folder 2)
- Valeria Symington, 1974-1991 (Box UP0003, Folder 3)
- MVC Newsletters FY '98-'99, 1998-1999 (Box UP0003, Folder 6)
- Mount Vernon Today '99-'00, 1999-2000 (Box UP0003, Folder 7)
- Sprague, R. Lee Thorndike, C'60, 1964-1979 (Box UP0003, Folder 9)
- IRS Audit, 1996-2001 (Box UP0003, Folder 11)
- Women in Power Residential Program, 1998 (Box UP0003, Folder 12)
- Academic Program Leadership Advisory, 1998 (Box UP0003, Folder 13)
- North Carolina and South Carolina [Alumnae], 2000 (Box UP0003, Folder 14)
- Erica Heden Scholarship, 1984-2002 (Box UP0003, Folder 15)
- Pending Resolution Banner Projects, 2001 (Box UP0003, Folder 16)
- Chart of Accounts, 1998-1999 (Box UP0003, Folder 25)
- Misc. Office Expenses, 2001 (Box UP0003, Folder 26)
- Ground Breaking 04/26/2000 (Box UP0003, Folder 27)
- Campaign Celebration, April 26, 2000, 04/26/2000 (Box UP0003, Folder 28)
- Major Gifts Conference for Deans 1999 (Box UP0003, Folder 29)
- Tennis Classic, 05/30/1998 (Box UP0003, Folder 30)
- 2000 Tennis Classic, 05/12/2000 (Box UP0003, Folder 31)
- England [Alumnae], 2000 (Box UP0003, Folder 32)
- New England [Alumnae], Fall 1999 (Box UP0003, Folder 33)
- South America [Alumnae], 2000 (Box UP0003, Folder 34)
- California [Alumnae], 04/1999 (Box UP0003, Folder 35)
- Pennsylvania [Alumane], 02/2001 (Box UP0003, Folder 36)
- Legacy Weekend 1999, 11/05/1999-11/07/1999 (Box UP0004, Folder 1)
- Legacy Weekend 2001, 04/04/2001 (Box UP0004, Folder 2)
- Legacy Weekend, Homecoming 2000 (Box UP0004, Folder 3)
- FY '99-'00 Budget, 1999-2000 (Box UP0004, Folder 4)
- FY '00-'01 Budget, 2000-2001 (Box UP0004, Folder 5)
- Pub File, 2001 (Box UP0004, Folder 6)
- April 2002 Alumnae Events, 04/2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 7)
- Mount Vernon Today 1997-2000 (Box UP0004, Folder 8)
- Historic Photos (Copies), undated (Box UP0004, Folder 9)
- Mount Vernon Today Summer 2002/Legacy Fund, 2001-2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 10)
- Mount Vernon Today Winter 2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 11)
- Lost MV alums 2000, 1999, 1999-2000 (Box UP0004, Folder 12)
- Hillwood - November 3, 2001, 11/03/2001 (Box UP0004, Folder 13)
- Former Trustees, 2001 (Box UP0004, Folder 14)
- 2001 Honor Roll Documents (Box UP0004, Folder 15)
- Centuries Campaign Report FY 2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 16)
- Annual Fund Report FY 2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 17)
- MVC Promotional Text, 1998-1999 (Box UP0004, Folder 18)
- Williamson/Hurlbut Clock Tower, 2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 19)
- SARC Winter Soiree, 02/21/2003 (Box UP0004, Folder 20)
- MVAA Governing Board Meeting, 03/22/2003 (Box UP0004, Folder 21)
- Women's History Month Lecture, 03/26/2003 (Box UP0004, Folder 22)
- Barbara Goodbody Exhibition, 04/10/2003 (Box UP0004, Folder 23)
- Cocktail Reception Event, 04/04/2003 (Box UP0004, Folder 24)
- Colonials Weekend, 10/11/2002-10/12/2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 25)
- Shannon Mouton - Payment Requests FY '03, 2003 (Box UP0004, Folder 26)
- Non-Cash Gifts 2001 (Box UP0004, Folder 27)
- Shannon Mouton - Payment Requests FY '03, 2003 (Box UP0004, Folder 28)
- FY '02 End of Year Expenses, 2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 29)
- Acheson P-Fund Creation, 2001-2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 30)
- Dickerson, Mary T., 1999-2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 32)
- Fernau, Anna, 1998-2004 (Box UP0004, Folder 33)
- Foggy Bottom Move, 2002-2003 (Box UP0004, Folder 35)
- Strategic Planning Meeting, 07/21/2001 (Box UP0004, Folder 36)
- Ruth Harris Ottman Trust, 1999-2000 (Box UP0004, Folder 39)
- Elizabeth Somers Center, 1998-2000 (Box UP0004, Folder 40)
- Elizabeth Somers Womens Leadership Programs, 2003-2004 (Box UP0004, Folder 41)
- Elizabeth Somers Portrait, 08/08/2000 (Box UP0004, Folder 42)
- Internet, 08/05/1995 (Box UP0004, Folder 43)
- MVC Faculty Lawsuit, 03/02/2001 (Box UP0004, Folder 44)
- Iconic, 02/12/2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 45)
- Pledge Forms, undated (Box UP0004, Folder 46)
- Marjorie Merriweather Post Foundation, 2001 (Box UP0004, Folder 47)
- Marjorie Merriweather Post Hillwood Museum, 2000 (Box UP0004, Folder 48)
- Webb Basement/File Room Mold Remediation, 06/07/2002 (Box UP0004, Folder 49)
- IN-Series 1998-1999 (Box UP0004, Folder 50)
- Newsletter Samples, 01/1998 (Box UP0004, Folder 51)
- Mount Vernon Today 2000-2001 (Box UP0004, Folder 52)
- MVC Development Audits, 11/03/1999 (Box UP0005, Folder 1)
- Development Audit, 1998-1999 (Box UP0005, Folder 2)
- Development Audit, 1993-1997 (Box UP0005, Folder 3)
- Current Restricted Fund, 1986-1987 (Box UP0005, Folder 4)
- Recap of Endowment Funds, 1990-1991 (Box UP0005, Folder 5)
- Lillie F. Webb/Library Authorization, 1991 (Box UP0005, Folder 6)
- Mount Vernon Building and Dedications, undated (Box UP0005, Folder 7)
- FY '99-'00 Annual Fund, 1999-2000 (Box UP0005, Folder 11)
- FY '99 MVC Annual Fund, 1999 (Box UP0005, Folder 12)
- FY '00-'01 Legacy Fund, 2000-2001 (Box UP0005, Folder 13)
- FY '98 MVC Annual Fund, 1997-1998 (Box UP0005, Folder 14)
- Jan 21, 2003 Reception at Dean Baxter's, 01/21/2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 15)
- Oracle, 2000-2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 17)
- Mount Vernon Today Fall 2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 19)
- Mount Vernon Today 2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 20)
- Nov 15 Luncheon, 11/15/2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 21)
- NCAS Nov 14 Dinner, 11/14/2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 22)
- Colonials Weekend 2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 23)
- NCAS Nov 15, 11/15/2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 24)
- NCAS Meetings Aug. 25-26, 08/25/2003-08/26/2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 25)
- Boston Trip 2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 26)
- April 27 2003 Senior Tea, 04/27/2003 (Box UP0005, Folder 27)
- Council for MV Oct 11, 10/11/2002 (Box UP0005, Folder 28)
- Mold FY '02, 2002 (Box UP0005, Folder 29)
- Council for MV - Oct 11, 2002, 10/11/2002 (Box UP0005, Folder 31)
- June 2002 Council Meeting, 06/2002 (Box UP0005, Folder 32)
- March 2001 Council Meeting, 03/2001 (Box UP0005, Folder 33)
- June 2001 Council Meeting, 06/2001 (Box UP0005, Folder 34)
- Council Meeting, January 30, 1999, 01/30/1999 (Box UP0005, Folder 35)
- Council Meeting, May 1999, 05/1999 (Box UP0005, Folder 36)
- Fall 1999 Council Meeting (Box UP0005, Folder 37)
- September 1999, Council Peer Screening, 09/1999 (Box UP0005, Folder 38)
- Commencement 1999 (Box UP0005, Folder 39)
- History Project Response Cards, undated (Box UP0005, Folder 40)
- MVC Honorary Degree Recipients, 1975-1999 (Box UP0005, Folder 41)
- Honors Program, 2001 (Box UP0005, Folder 42)
- 2001 Honor Roll (Box UP0005, Folder 43)
- MV Honor Roll FY 2000 (Box UP0005, Folder 44)
- Council Meeting, 03/01/2002 (Box UP0005, Folder 45)
- Lost Alums, 2002 (Box UP0005, Folder 46)
- Mount Vernon Today [loose], 2007 (Box UP0005, Folder 47)
- Planning FY '98-'99, 1998-1999 (Box UP0006, Folder 1)
- 2001-2002 Operating Plan (Box UP0006, Folder 2)
- 2002-2003 Operating Plan (Box UP0006, Folder 3)
- FY '99-'00 Operating Plan, 1999-2000 (Box UP0006, Folder 4)
- FY '00-'01 Operating Plan, 2000-2001 (Box UP0006, Folder 5)
- FY '99-'00 In-Series, 1999-2000 (Box UP0006, Folder 6)
- Chicago [Alumnae], 1999 (Box UP0006, Folder 7)
- Richmond, Tidewater, etc. Trip July/August 2007, 07/2007-08/2007 (Box UP0006, Folder 8)
- New York Event October 2000, 10/2000 (Box UP0006, Folder 9)
- New York/CT/NJ January 2000, 01/2000 (Box UP0006, Folder 10)
- Texas Receptions 06/2000 (Box UP0006, Folder 11)
- South Florida, 04/1999 (Box UP0006, Folder 12)
- Florida 3/99-4/99, 03/1999-04/1999 (Box UP0006, Folder 13)
- Florida 3/2000, 03/2000 (Box UP0006, Folder 14)
- Mount Vernon Campus Photos (March 2004), 03/2004 (Box UP0006, Folder 15)
- Seals and Logos, undated (Box UP0006, Folder 16)
- Council for MVC 1998-1999 (Box UP0006, Folder 17)
- Centuries Campaign [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 1)
- Proposals 1998-2002 [3.5" diskette] (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 2)
- Old Sarah Files from Colleague Computer [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 3)
- Mount Vernon College Administration May 1998-Jan 1999 [3.5" diskette], 05/1998-01/1999 (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 4)
- Mount Vernon Administration July 1999, WIP [3.5" diskette], 07/1999 (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 5)
- The Council for Mount Vernon [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 6)
- Administration Jan 1999-July 1999 [3.5" diskette], 01/1999-07/1999 (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 7)
- Campus Plan-new, E. Somers Center Blurg, Mount Vernon Case Study [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 8)
- History Project, Dear Daughters, MVS and MVC Archives [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 9)
- Mount Vernon Campaign Case Statement [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 10)
- Files for Clock Tower Event [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 11)
- Administration 2001-2002 [3.5" diskette] (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 12)
- Mount Vernon Correspondence July 1999 [3.5" diskette], 07/1999 (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 13)
- Mount Vernon College Correspondence 1998-1999 [3.5" diskette] (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 14)
- 2000-2001 Administration [3.5" diskette] (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 15)
- MVC CCAS [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 16)
- 2001-2002 Correspondence [3.5" diskette] (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 17)
- 2000-2001 Correspondence [3.5" diskette] (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 18)
- Proposals August 2002 [3.5" diskette], 08/2002 (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 19)
- Mount Vernon Centuries Campaign [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 20)
- Unidentified [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 21)
- Jan 1999-July 1999, Correspondence [3.5" diskette], 01/1999-07/1999 (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 22)
- Harris Directory - Text [3.5" diskette], undated (Box UP0006, Floppy disk 23)
- Panoramic photo, Class of 1969, 06/09/1969 (Box UP0006, Loose-material 1)
- Mount Vernon College Alumnae Directory, 1989 (Box UP0006, Loose-material 2)